<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../../lib/pkp/dtd/helpTopic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000024.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2012 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Editorial Process - Track Director's Role - Review - Review Version 
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="editorial/topic/000024" locale="en_US" title="Review Version" toc="editorial/toc/000011" key="editorial.trackDirectorsRole.review.reviewVersion">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p><em>Establishing the submission's Review Version</em>. With each submission, the Track Director clicks on the file name next to the Review Version list item which, is almost always the version submitted by the Author, to check if the original file can serve as Review Version (ie., that there are no identifying markers on it). If not, it should be downloaded, revised to serve as Review Version, re-uploaded. The Track Director can then select between the two versions two submit to the Review process.</p>
		<p>The Track Director can also opt to fix minor problems with the original file using a word processor to make the changes, saving the file to the computer and then uploading the file. </p>
            <p>The Track Director should also check whether Supplementary Files can be shared with Reviewers. Though the checked box expresses the Author's wish to present files to Reviewers in submission, the Track Director can uncheck it and press the Record link if they are unsuitable in any way.</p>
		<p><em>Inadequately prepared submissions</em>. If the Author has clearly failed to meet the conference's Author Guidelines and Submission Requirements, the Track Director can notify the Author that the work needs to be resubmitted. The Author can then resubmit the improved version by email directly to the Track Director, who can then upload it as the Review Version. The Track Director can also decide that the submission is simply not suitable for the conference and notify the Author to that effect, and send the submission to the Archives.</p>]]>	</section>
</topic>
