<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../topic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000026.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2008 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Editorial Process - Track Director's Role - Review - Director Decision
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="editorial/topic/000026" locale="en_US" title="Director Decision" toc="editorial/toc/000011" key="editorial.trackDirectorsRole.review.directorDecision">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p>Once all the reviews are gathered, the Track Director must arrive at a decision on the submission.</p>
		<p><i>Recording the Decision</i>. The Track Director selects a decision from the dropdown menu: Accept Submission, Revisions Required, or Decline Submission, and press "Record Decision".</p>
		<p>The Track Director should outline the basis of their decision to the Author in Director/Author Correspondence (as the Author cannot see the Decision recorded). The Track Director can also upload a Director Version of the submission possibly with suggestions or comments. Finally, the Track Director must email the Author using the Notify Author email icon. Reviewer Comments can be imported into this email by clicking on "Import Peer Reviews" above the email subject line. Please note that comments designated by the Reviewer as director-only are not imported.</p>
		<p>If the Track Director selects Accept Submission, then after notifying the Author, the Track Director can select a version of submission and click on "Send" by Move to Layout. The version is from among the versions of Director and Author. The default Director Version is simply the Review Version, and the Track Director can make changes to this version &mdash; restoring the author's name, for example &mdash; and upload it as Director Version.</p>
		<p>If the Track Director selects Revisions Required, the Author should revise the current version to satisfy the demand and upload the revised version once more to be decided by the Track Director. </p>
		<p>If the Track Director selects Decline Submission, the submission moves to the Archives list, with its status shown as Declined.</p>
            <p><i>Revisions Required<i>. The Track Director can initiate a second round of review for a submission by selecting Revisions Required as the Director Decision. The Track Director then notifies the Author by email and includes an outline of what needs to be done with the submission prior to resubmitting for review. When the Author re-submits a version for review, it appears under Author Version, and the Track Director designates it for resubmission. It then becomes the Review Version for Round 2 (and should again be checked for anonymity, and if necessary, uploaded again under Review Version). The Reviewers from Round 1 will still be there, although their reviews and recommendations will be cleared and placed under "View Regrets, Cancels". The Track Director can activate the request to each of the Reviewers from Round 1 by clicking on the email icon under Request, or the Track Director can use Clear Reviewer and select another Reviewer for Round 2. The Director/Author Correspondence for Round 1 is also placed under "View Regrets, Cancels" of this submission. </p> ]]>	
	</section>
</topic>
