<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../../lib/pkp/dtd/helpTopic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000015.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2012 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Editorial Process - Reviewer's Role - Review
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="editorial/topic/000015" locale="en_US" title="Review" toc="editorial/toc/000003" key="editorial.reviewersRole.review">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p>The Review process is divided into five steps, intended to lead the Reviewer through the Review process.</p>
		<p><em>Step 1</em><br />First, the Reviewer has to inform the Track Director whether he/she will undertake the review. The decision should be made after reviewing the submission's metadata and abstract and perhaps looking at the submission, by clicking on the file name in Step 2 (depending on the conference's policies, the file may not be available prior to the Reviewer agreeing to review it). The due date under Review Schedule might also be a factor influencing the Reviewer's decision. Once the Reviewer responses, it is recorded under Response of Review Schedule.  </p>
		<p><em>If unable to do the review</em>. The Reviewer who is unable to do the review clicks on the email icon by "Unable to do the review", which leads to a prepared email to the Track Director, which the Reviewer can modify to indicate, if they wish, why they are unable to do the review (e.g., timing, conflict of interest, lack of expertise, etc.).</p>
		<p><em>If able to do the review</em>. The Reviewer who is able to do the review clicks on the email icon by "Will do the review", which leads to a prepared email to the Track Director, and which will indicate to the Track Director and Author that the review is underway.</p>
		<p><em>Step 2</em><br />The Reviewer is prompted to read the Reviewer Guidelines, which are printed at the bottom of the page. These Guidelines have been entered by the Conference Manager in Scheduled Conference Setup Step 3.1.</p>
		<p><em>Step 3</em><br />
		The Reviewer must then review all submitted materials, including the abstract and any uploaded files, if present. The Reviewer will be able to download and view all presentation files, and supplementary files if permitted by the Author and the Director.</p>
		<p><em>Step 4</em><br />The Reviewer clicks on the Review icon and is presented with two text boxes where the review can be either typed or pasted: the first for both Director and Author, and the second for the Director only. The Reviewer may enter or paste reviews into these boxes and press the "Save" button at the bottom of the form to return and make changes later. The Reviewer may return to make any changes until a Recommendation is chosen, indicating the Review process is completed.</p>
		<p><em>Step 5</em><br />The Reviewer also has the option, in addition to entering a Review, of uploading a file for the Track Director and/or the Author. The file may be a Reviewer-annotated version of the submission or some relevant data or other materials that will assist Track Director and/or Author. It will be at the Track Director's discretion whether the file should be shown to the Author.</p>
		<p><em>Step 6</em><br />The Reviewer must then select a submission recommendation from the dropdown menu: Accept Submission; Revisions Required; Submit Elsewhere; Decline Submission; or See Comments. When the Reviewer clicks the Submit Review to Director button, they then have to fill out a prepared email for the Track Director. The email can be edited by the Reviewer before sending. Once submitted, it is recorded under Review Submitted of Review Schedule. The Reviewer will not be able to click the Submit Review button until a review has been entered or a file has been uploaded.</p>
		<p>Once the Reviewer has made a recommendation, the review is closed and no further changes can be made.</p>]]>	
	</section>
</topic>
