<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../../lib/pkp/dtd/helpTopic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000016.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2012 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Editorial Process - Author's Role - Submissions
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="editorial/topic/000016" locale="en_US" title="Submissions" toc="editorial/toc/000004" key="editorial.authorsRole.submissions">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p>Once logged in, an Author can visit their Active Submissions list by checking their Author's User Home page. If the scheduled conference is currently accepting submissions, the Author will see a link to start the submission process at the bottom of the page. The Author can also visit an Archive of past submission by clicking the Archive link under the Active Submissions heading.</p>
		<p>If the conference is currently accepting submissions, the Author must go through a multi-step submission process, the amount of steps depending on what the scheduled conference requires for a completed submission.</p>
		<p><em>Abstract Only</em><br />If the scheduled conference only requires an abstract, the submission process will be two steps long. For the first step the Author will have to agree to certain requirements, such as an established submission checklist; potentially a copyright notice; and so on. For the second step the Author will have to provide authorship and indexing information, as well as the submission title and abstract.</p>
		<p><em>Full Proposal</em><br />If the scheduled conference requires a full proposal, the submission process will be much the same as above, but instead of an abstract the Author will have to upload a full document (for example, a .doc, .wpd or .odt file) to the system.</p>
		<p><em>Abstract and Proposal Together</em><br />If the scheduled conference requires both an abstract and a proposal, the submission process will involve all above steps before completion.</p>
		<p><em>Abstract Followed by Presentation</em><br />If the scheduled conference requires an abstract first followed by a presentation later, the Author will initially only have to enter an abstract along with some indexing information. If the abstract passes the review process the Author will be invited to submit their full presentation, which may also go through a review process.</p>
		
		<p>There are a handful of other possible configurations:</p>
		<ul>
			<li>The system may allow only individual presentations, or it may allow the Author(s) to submit multiple-presentation sessions, or both; </li>
			<li>The system may also prompt for a supplementary file upload, which is optional.</li>
		</ul>
		]]>	
	</section>
</topic>
