<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../../lib/pkp/dtd/helpTopic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000025.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2012 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Editorial Process - Track Director's Role - Review - Peer Review 
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="editorial/topic/000025" locale="en_US" title="Peer Review" toc="editorial/toc/000011" key="editorial.trackDirectorsRole.review.peerReview">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p><em>Ensuring a blind Peer Review</em>. See instructions for {help_topic key="editorial.directorsRole.blindPeerReview" text="Ensuring a Blind Peer Review"}. Once the Review Version is decided, the Track Director can start the Peer Review process. The Track Director first clicks on the Select Reviewer link, which brings the Track Director a list of Reviewers, with relevant information about their reviewing interests, number of completed and ongoing reviews, average time to complete a review, date of most recently accepted review, and their ratings (if applicable). The Track Director then clicks on the Assign link under Action in an entry of a Reviewer to be selected for the assignment.</p>
		<p><em>Changing Reviewers</em>. If the Track Director realizes that the chosen Reviewer is unfit for the assignment, by clicking on the Clear Reviewer button, the name of this Reviewer is removed before initiating the review (once the Reviewer has been notified by email, this button changes to say Cancel Review Request). To replace a Reviewer who has been notified, the Track Director clicks on the Cancel Review Request button which leads to a cancel email to be sent to the current Reviewer. The Track Director then clicks on the Select Reviewer link to assign another Reviewer, and sends out the request email to that Reviewer. If a Track Director cancels a review but the Reviewer has already updated the submission indicating that the review is done, the Track Director can re-initiate the review by sending a request email to a new Reviewer. A list of the Reviewers who declined the request to review or were cancelled by the Track Director can be found by clicking the View Regrets, Cancels link.</p>
		<p><em>Requesting and initiating a Peer Review</em>. The Track Director clicks on the email icon under Request which opens a prepared email to the Reviewer. The Track Director can change the required time for completing the review in the email, which is set by the Conference Manager in Scheduled Conference Setup Step 3.2. The Track Director can also change the due date for completing review by clicking on the date that appears under Due.</p>
		<p><em>The Reviewer responds on the web site</em>. Typically, the Reviewer responds to the invitation to review by logging in the conference website and notifying the Track Director with a prepared email that the review will or will not be undertaken as requested. If the Reviewer declines the request, their names go to the View Regrets, Cancels page. The Conference Manager has the option in Scheduled Conference Setup Step 3.2 of activating an automated email reminder to be sent to Reviewers who do not respond to the request within required period of time.</p>
		<p><em>The Reviewer responds by email</em>. Instead of going to the conference website, the Reviewer can send the Track Director an email to indicate either accepting or declining the review request. The Track Director can record this decision by going to the Review page and choosing either Will do the Review or Unable to do the Review links, next to the Director to Enter line. The first selection will allow the Reviewer to access the submission online, and the second will clear the Reviewer's name from the Peer Review, and place it in the View Regrets, Cancels page. The Track Director can then select another Reviewer by following the procedures in "Changing Reviewers".</p>
		<p><em>The Reviewer completes the review online</em>. The Reviewer completes the review by entering their comments in Review (based on the Reviewer Guidelines which have been entered in Scheduled Conference Setup Step 3.2 by the Conference Manager) and selecting a Recommendation from the dropdown menu: Accept Submission, Revisions Required, Submit Elsewhere, Decline Submission, See Comments. The Reviewer may also opt to upload files, whether an annotated version of the submission or some additional relevant information, which the Track Director will decide whether the author will access by checking Let Author View File. The Conference Manager has the option in Scheduled Conference Setup Step 3.2 of activating an automated email reminder to be sent to Reviewers who do not complete the review within required period of time. The Track Director can also send a reminder by using the email icon under Request, with the content modified. Alternatively, the Track Director can send an email by clicking on the Send Reminder link next to Recommendation. </p>
		<p><em>One-Click Review Access</em>. If the Conference Manager has enabled One-Click Reviewer Access in Scheduled Conference Setup Step 3.2, then the Reviewer will receive an invited email containing a special URL that takes him/her directly to the Review page for the submission. Nevertheless, Reviewers are required to log to with access any other pages. </p>]]>	
	</section>
</topic>
