<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../topic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000022.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2008 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Editorial Process - Director's Role - Summary Page - Submission Management
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="editorial/topic/000022" locale="en_US" title="Submission Management" toc="editorial/toc/000006" key="editorial.directorsRole.summaryPage.submissionManagement">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p>Various aspects of submission management can be undertaken from a Summary Page.</p>
		<p><i>Submission</i><br />The Director can have a general picture of the submission, its title, author and submitter names, submission type; email the author and submitter; review the submitted original file and supplementary files; check if the submission is in the appropriate conference track.</p>
		<p>Before assigning a Track Director to manage the Review phase of the submission, the Director should click on the linked submission title to open the file and ensure that it appears to be suitable for review.</p>
		<p><i>Directors</i><br />In order for the submission to proceed to the Review phase, the Director must assign a Track Director from the listing. If Track Directors are not used by this conference, the Director may select "Add Self", and personally oversee the review phase. Several Track Directors can be assigned with various tasks to a submission. This action will send an automated email to the Track Director with notification of the assignment.</p>
		<p><i>Status</i><br />The Director can check the current status of submission, and dates of its initiation and last modification. </p>
		<p>If the submission is obviously not appropriate for the conference, the Director may click on "Archive Submission", which will initiate an email to the Author indicating that the submission will not be proceeded to review. Once the email is sent, the submission will be moved to the Archives. The assigned Track Director is also able to take this action.</p>
           <p><i>Submission Metadata</i><br />Metadata entered by the Author while submission is shown here, and can be edited by the Director. The assigned Track Director is also able to take this action. </p>]]>	
	</section>
</topic>
