<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../topic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000027.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2008 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Editorial Process - Track Director's Role - Review - Layout
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="editorial/topic/000027" locale="en_US" title="Layout" toc="editorial/toc/000011" key="editorial.trackDirectorsRole.review.layout">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p>The Track Director can click on "Complete" button directly after making Director Decision, and the submission is added to the list of accepted Presentations as it is. If changes need to be made in its layout, the Track Director can select a version and use "Send" button next to "Move to Layout", and click on "Complete" when Layout is done. </p>
		         <p><i>Galley Format</i>When a selected version is sent to Layout, it appears under Galley Format in Layout section, and also a copy next to "File". This file can be downloaded and be converted to PDF and/or HTML format. With "Galley" selected next to "Upload File to", the PDF and/or HTML version of the file can be uploaded using "Browse" and "Upload" buttons. On Edit a Layout Galley page, Label (i.e., PDF, HTML) is added for identifying the file format. Press "Save" button to return to the previous page. Once uploaded, the PDF and/or HTML version will appear under Galley Format. For all files listed, they can be viewed proofs, edited, deleted, and reordered. </p>
		         <p><i>Supplementary Files</i>For supplementary files, they go thorugh the same procedures as the submission elaborated above, except that "Supp.files" is selected instead of "Galley" next to "Upload File to". </p>
                 <p>If the already uploaded files need to be made changes later, click on "Edit" by the file name, and on Edit page, upload a revised version next to "Replace File", click on "Save", the current file will be updated. </p>]]>	
	</section>
</topic>
