<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../../lib/pkp/dtd/helpTopic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000000.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2012 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Conference Management Main 
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="conference/topic/000000" locale="en_US" title="Conference Managment" toc="index/toc/000000" subtoc="conference/toc/000000" key="conference.index">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p>The Conference Manager role breaks down into three main administrative tasks, all available from the Conference Management page from their User Home:</p>
		
<ol>
<li><em>Set up the hosted conference website.</em> From the Conference Management page the Conference Manager should first visit the {help_topic key="conference.generalManagement.websiteManagement" text="Website Management"} page and follow the six steps to a conference website. The Conference Manager should then establish a scheduled conference by visiting the {help_topic key="conference.generalManagement.scheduledConferences" text="Scheduled Conferences"} page. See {help_topic key="conference.generalManagement.index" text="General Management"} for a detailed breakdown.</li>
<li><em>Set up the scheduled conference.</em> After the Conference Manager has established a scheduled conference, the conference name will appear on their Conference Management page, along with a list of configuration pages, under the <strong>Current Conferences</strong> heading. The Conference Manager should first visit the {help_topic key="conference.currentConferences.setup" text="Setup"} page and follow the three steps to a scheduled conference, and then visit the rest of the Current Conferences pages in turn. For more information, see {help_topic key="conference.currentConferences.index" text="Current Conferences"}. </li>
<li><em>Administer users.</em> The Conference Manager can register new users for with the system and assign them roles specific to their hosted conference, and can enroll already-created users with their hosted conference. See {help_topic key="conference.users.index" text="Users"} and {help_topic key="conference.roles.index" text="Roles"} for more information on each.</li>
</ol>]]>	
	</section>
</topic>

