<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../../lib/pkp/dtd/helpTopic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000017.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2012 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Conference Management - Current Conferences - Organizing Team
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="conference/topic/000017" locale="en_US" title="Organizing Team" toc="conference/toc/000002"  key="conference.currentConferences.organizingTeam">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p>OCS displays an organizing team list on the About the Conference page: this list includes team names, which in turn link to member biographies and email addresses. The Conference Manager can control how the scheduled conference displays its organizing team from the Conference Site Management Organizing Team page: namely, whether the organizing team is culled from the system's assigned roles (Conference Manager, Director, Track Director, etc.) or custom-made.</p>
		<p>If the first choice (create teams from assigned roles) is selected, the Conference Manager will have to do no further work and the team will be populated automatically. If the second choice is selected, the Conference Manager will have to define organizing team titles (Directors; Managers; etc.) and populate them with users from the system database.</p>
		<p>To switch from one method to the other, the Conference Manager must click on the appropriate radio button and then hit the Record button.]]>
	</section>
	<section title="Creating an Organizing Team Title">
		<![CDATA[<p>Clicking the Create Organizing Team Title link at the bottom of the page will allow the Conference Manager to specify a custom title. When the new title has been filled in and the Save button pressed, the title will appear in the Organizing Team Title list.</p>]]>
	</section>
	<section title="Managing the Organizing Team">
		<![CDATA[<p>Once a title exists, the Conference Manager can add enrolled users to it by clicking the Membership link, and then Add Member on the Membership list page. Multiple users can be assigned to a title; they can also be easily deleted and their display order sorted from the Membership list page. Please note that a user does not have to be enrolled in an administrative role to be added to a title: this can be especially useful for advisory boards, and so on.</p>
		
		<p>Title names can be edited by clicking the Edit link beside their name, and can be deleted by clicking the Delete link. Their display order in About the Conference can also be rearranged by using the up and down arrows.</p>
		
		<p>Conference Managers can also mass-email all members of a title by clicking the email icon next to the title name.</p>]]>
	</section>
</topic>
