<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../../lib/pkp/dtd/helpTopic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000022.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2012 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Conference Management - Current Conferences - Scheduler
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="conference/topic/000022" locale="en_US" title="Scheduler" toc="conference/toc/000002"  key="conference.currentConferences.scheduler">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p>With the options available on the Scheduler page, the Conference Manager can create locations (buildings and rooms within buildings) to which presentations can be assigned, and can create special conference events. Once created, the conference schedule will be available from the Conference Information links in the sidebar and on the scheduled conference's home page.</p>]]> 
	</section>
	<section title="Managing Buildings and Rooms">
		<![CDATA[<p>The Conference Manager can create one or more buildings, each with one or more rooms. To create a building the Conference Manager has to click the Scheduler link, then the Buildings and Rooms link followed by the Create New Building link. The Conference Manager must assign the new building a name and abbreviation, and can enter an optional description. Buildings that have been added to the system can be edited, deleted, and arranged for sort order from the Buildings and Rooms page.</p>  
		<p>For each building there is also a Rooms link: clicking this will display a list of rooms associated to that building, with a link to Create a New Room at the bottom of the page. The Conference Manager must provide a name and abbreviation for each room, and can provide an optional description as well. Again, rooms that have been added to the system can be edited, deleted and arranged for display purposes from the Rooms page.</p>
		<p>It is advisable to add directions to the description of any buildings and rooms added to the system: these directions will be available from the Conference Schedule page.</p>
		<p>Special events cannot be assigned a building/room location, so such locations should not be entered into the system.</p> ]]>
	</section>
	<section title="Managing Special Events">
		<![CDATA[<p>Special events that fall outside of the realm of presentations, panels, keynotes and so on can also be added to the conference schedule. Clicking on the Special Events link available from the Scheduler page will bring the Conference Manager to the Special Events page, where events can be created, added and deleted. To create a new event the Conference Manager must click on the Create a New Special Event link, fill out the name of the event; the date; the start and end time; and add a description, if needed. Since it is not possible to assign these events to buildings and rooms, it is advisable to put location information and directions in the description.</p> ]]>
	</section>
	<section title="Scheduling Presentations">
		<![CDATA[<p>Clicking the Schedule Presentations link from the Scheduler page will display a list of all accepted presentations, and the option to schedule them by location and by date. While the location is an optional flag (if a presentation does not have a location set, it will appear in the conference schedule regardless) the date and time must be set.</p>]]>
	</section>
</topic>