<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../topic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000007.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2008 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Conference Management - General Management - Announcements 
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="conference/topic/000007" locale="en_US" title="Announcements" toc="conference/toc/000001" key="conference.genneralManagement.announcements">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p>OCS enables Conference Manager to post announcements that are then available to readers who visit the site. Posted announcements appear on the Announcements page and, optionally, on the conference's homepage.</p>
		<p><i>Deploying the announcement module</i>. The Conference Manager must indicate in Website Management Setup 2.4 that the conference announcements will be added. Once selected, Announcements function will appear under General Management. In addition, the Conference Manager must indicate whether or not announcements should be displayed on the conference's homepage, and specify the number of the most recent announcements to be displayed. An introductory text may also be provided that will appear at the top of the Announcements page.</p>
		<p><i>Creating Announcements</i>.<p>Click on "Announcements" under General Management on Conference Site Management page. First, select "Announcement Types", "Create Announcement Type", fill in an announcement type name. Then select "Announcements", "Create New Announcement". Choose an option from the dropdown menu of "Type" and "Scheduled Conference", provide a title for the announcement, and both a short description and a full description of the announcement. The short description is displayed to readers as a summary of the announcement, whereas the full description is displayed when readers select to read more details. An expiry date may also be specified, with which announcements will no longer be displayed to readers once the expiry date has passed.</p>]]>
	</section>
</topic>
