<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../../lib/pkp/dtd/helpTopic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000043.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2012 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Conference Management - General Management - Reading Tools - Contexts
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="conference/topic/000043" locale="en_US" title="Contexts" toc="conference/toc/000009" key="conference.generalManagement.readingTools.contexts">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p>Each Related Items version consists of multiple contexts with each context in turn consisting of a number of searches. For example, the Related Item version "Agriculture" includes a list of contexts; its "Pay-per-view" context includes links search engines for pay-per-view services like Ingenta, Ebrary, and so on. These searches, and the contexts they are grouped into, can be created, edited or deleted. Both can be reordered.</p>]]>
</section>
<section title="Context Configuration Options">
	<![CDATA[
		<p><em>Metadata:</em><br /> The Conference Manager can edit the title, abbreviation, and description of the context. There are also options to determine whether the author's name (e.g., for use with Author's Other Works, or citations to this paper), or geographical indexing terms will be used for the searching of the database in question. Another option, used with Definition of Terms, allows the reader to select the search term by double clicking on any word in the html text. The Conference Manager can use these options to configure their reading tools.</p>
		<p><em>Searches:</em><br /> The Conference Manager can edit or delete the search URL for each database. For each database, a base URL is provided that will enable the reader to learn more about the database, as well as the search-engine-specific URL string itself. There are two types of searches that can be set up, a GET search, and if that will not work with the database, a POST search is also supported.</p>
		<p><em>Delete:</em><br /> This will delete the context in question from the Context list. This can be undone by clicking the Restore Versions to Defaults link at the bottom of the Versions page, however this will revert <em>all</em> changes in all versions.</p>]]>
	</section>
</topic>
