<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../../lib/pkp/dtd/helpTopic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000007.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2012 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Conference Management - General Management - Announcements 
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="conference/topic/000007" locale="en_US" title="Announcements" toc="conference/toc/000001" key="conference.genneralManagement.announcements">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p>The Conference Manager can post announcements that are then available to readers who visit the site. Posted announcements appear on the Announcements page available from the top navigation bar, and optionally on the conference's homepage.</p>
		<p><em>Deploying the announcement module</em>. The Conference Manager must first indicate in Website Management Setup 2.4 that the hosted conference will be using announcements. Once enabled, the Announcements function will appear under General Management as a link. In addition, the Conference Manager must indicate whether or not announcements should be displayed on the conference's homepage, and specify the number of the most recent announcements to be displayed. An introductory text may also be provided: this will appear at the top of the Announcements page.</p>
		<p><em>Creating Announcements</em>. To add an announcement to the hosted conference site, the Conference Manager must click on the "Announcements" link under the General Management heading on the Conference Site Management page.</p>
		
		<p>The Conference Manager can create multiple announcement types (for example, Site News, Conference News, News for Presenters, etc.) by clicking the Announcement Types link, and then Create Announcement Type, and then filling in an announcement type name (creating announcement types is optional, and announcements don't need to be assigned a type).</p>
		<p>To create a new announcement from the Announcements page the Conference Manager must click the Create New Announcement link and fill in or select from the following options. The announcement can appear with all scheduled conferences, or only one of them; can be tagged with an announcement type, if at least one type has been created; and can be given an expiry date whereby the announcement will be removed from the Announcements display page. The Announcement title, short description and description fields are all mandatory. </p>]]>
	</section>
</topic>
