<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../../lib/pkp/dtd/helpTopic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000027.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2012 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Conference Management - Users - Create New User 
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="conference/topic/000027" locale="en_US" title="Create New User" toc="conference/toc/000003" key="conference.users.createNewUser">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p>The Conference Manager can create new users and assign them roles specific to a hosted conference, and optionally to a scheduled conference.</p>]]>
	</section>
	<section title="Creating Users within a Hosted Conference">
		<![CDATA[<p>It is possible to create new users regardless of whether there is a current scheduled conference. The Conference Manager can click the Create New User link under the Users heading, and fill out the subsequent form.</p>
		<p>Mandatory fields include First Name; Last Name; User Name; Password/Repeat Password; and Email. The Conference Manager can opt to have the system generate a random password; can send the user a welcome email with their registration information; and can additionally require that the user change their password when first logging in.</p>
		<p>Please note that with this method Conference Managers can only register users with no assigned role, or as Conference Managers themselves -- to create a user with a role specific to a scheduled Conference, follow the method below.</p>  ]]>
	</section>
	<section title="Creating Users within a Scheduled Conference">
		<![CDATA[<p>If a scheduled conference has been created by the Conference Manager, users can be created and given roles specific to that scheduled conference, ie. Director; Track Director; Author; Reviewer; and Reader. To do so, the Conference Manager can click the Roles link under the scheduled conference heading in question; click the Create New User link; and then fill out the subsequent form, making sure to choose any applicable roles.</p>
		<p>The Conference Manager can also click the specific role title from underneath the scheduled conference heading in question, and create a new user who will be automatically enrolled with that role.</p> ]]>
	</section>
</topic>
