<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../../lib/pkp/dtd/helpTopic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000035.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2012 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Conference Management - General Management - Website Management - About the Conference
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="conference/topic/000035" locale="en_US" title="About the Conference" toc="conference/toc/000005" key="conference.generalManagement.websiteManagement.about">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p><em>Title</em> and <em>Conference Description:</em><br /> The contents of these fields are automatically filled in with information specified by the Site Administrator when the hosted conference was initially created, but can be modified by the Conference Manager here. The conference title and description will appear in the list of hosted conferences from the site's index page.</p>
		<p><em>Principal Contact for Conference Website:</em><br /> This is the principal contact information for the hosted conference as a whole. Primary contacts can also be assigned to individual scheduled conferences. </p>
		<p><em>Copyright Notice:</em><br /> OCS comes with a default copyright notice, which can be modified. It can be made mandatory that authors agree to the copyright notice as part of the submission process, and the Creative Commons license logo can be posted on the conference web site.</p>
		<p><em>Archive Access Policy:</em><br /> The Conference Manager can control how conference archives are accessed and what user levels can comment on archived presentations. See {help_topic key="conference.generalManagement.websiteManagement.additional" text="Access to Conference Presentations"} for additional access settings.</p>
		<p><em>Privacy Statement:</em><br /> OCS comes with a default privacy statement, which can be modified.</p>
		<p><em>Add Item to Appear in "About the Conference":</em><br /> Additional information may be added, and will be displayed as a new entry under Policies on the conference's About page. By clicking on "Add About Item", another new entry may be added below. </p>]]>
	</section>
</topic>
