<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE locale SYSTEM "../../lib/pkp/dtd/locale.dtd">

<!--
  * ocs2-devel/locale/en_US/admin.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2012 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Localization strings for the en_US (English) locale.
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<locale name="en_US" full_name = "English">
	<message key="admin.languages.primaryLocaleInstructions">This will be the default language for the site and any hosted conferences.</message>
	<message key="admin.languages.supportedLocalesInstructions">Select all locales to support on the site. The selected locales will be available for use by all conferences hosted on the site, and also appear in a language select menu to appear on each site page (which can be overridden on conference-specific pages). If multiple locales are not selected, the language toggle menu will not appear and extended language settings will not be available to conferences.</message>
	<message key="admin.locale.maybeIncomplete">Marked locales may be incomplete.</message>
	<message key="admin.languages.confirmUninstall">Are you sure you want to uninstall this locale? This may affect any hosted conferences currently using the locale.</message>
	<message key="admin.languages.installNewLocalesInstructions">Select any additional locales to install support for in this system. Locales must be installed before they can be used by hosted conferences. See the OCS documentation for information on adding support for new languages.</message>
	<message key="admin.auth.enableSyncProfiles">Enable user profile synchronization (if supported by this authentication plug-in). User profile information will be automatically updated from the remote source when a user logs in, and profile changes (including password changes) made within OCS will be automatically updated on the remote source. If this option is not enabled OCS profile information will be kept separate from remote source profile information.</message>
	<message key="admin.auth.enableSyncPasswords">Enable user password modification (if supported by this authentication plug-in). Enabling this option allows users to modify their password from within OCS and to use the OCS "lost password" feature to reset a forgotten password. These functions will be unavailable to users with this authentication source if this option is not enabled.</message>
	<message key="admin.auth.enableCreateUsers">Enable user creation (if supported by this authentication plug-in). Users created within OCS with this authentication source will be automatically added to the remote authentication source if they do not already exist. Additionally, if this source is the default authentication source, OCS accounts created through user registration will also be added to the remote authentication source.</message>
	<message key="admin.systemVersion">OCS Version</message>
	<message key="admin.systemConfiguration">OCS Configuration</message>
	<message key="admin.systemConfigurationDescription"><![CDATA[OCS configuration settings from <tt>config.inc.php</tt>.]]></message>
	<message key="admin.hostedConferences">Hosted Conferences</message>
	<message key="admin.settings.conferenceRedirect">Conference redirect</message>
	<message key="admin.settings.conferenceRedirectInstructions">Requests to the main site will be redirected to this conference. This may be useful if the site is hosting only a single conference, for example.</message>
	<message key="admin.settings.noConferenceRedirect">Do not redirect</message>
	<message key="admin.auth.ocs">OCS User Database</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.conferenceSettings">Conference Settings</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.noneCreated">No conferences have been created.</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.confirmDelete">Are you sure you want to permanently delete this conference and all of its contents?</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.create">Create Conference</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.createInstructions">You will automatically be enrolled as the manager of this conference. After creating a new conference, enter it as a manager to continue with its setup and user enrollment.</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.urlWillBe">This should be a single short word or acronym that identifies the conference. The conference's URL will be {$sampleUrl}</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.form.titleRequired">A title is required.</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.form.pathRequired">A path is required.</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.form.pathAlphaNumeric">The path can contain only alphanumeric characters, underscores, and hyphens, and must begin and end with an alphanumeric character.</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.form.pathExists">The selected path is already in use by another conference.</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.enableConferenceInstructions">Enable this conference to appear publicly on the site</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.scheduleConferenceInstructions">Proceed to schedule a conference next.</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.conferenceDescription">Conference description</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.conferenceDescriptionInstructions">The conference description identifies the ongoing mission of this conference. It appears on the main conference page, as well as all of the conference's convention pages.</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.importOCS1">Import from OCS 1</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.importOCS1.editMigratedConference">Edit Migrated Conference</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.importOCS1.conflict.desc">Some user accounts had conflicting information. OCS 1.x allows multiple user accounts to share the same email address, while OCS 2.x does not. In the list below, the second account listed has had a temporary email account assigned to it. These should be corrected by hand, either by assigning a different email account, or by merging accounts.</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.importOCS1.errors.desc">The following errors were encountered when migrating from the OCS 1.x conference into OCS 2.x.</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.importOCS1.conflict">{$firstUsername} ({$firstName}) and {$secondUsername} ({$secondName})</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.importOCS1Instructions"><![CDATA[Consult the UPGRADE document distributed with OCS for detailed information on migrating data from OCS 1 to OCS 2. Note that this process will NOT create a completely configured OCS 2 conference; only certain items (e.g. papers) will be imported. <strong>All imported users will need to reset their passwords. It is strongly suggested that the Conference Director review all imported information before launching the conference website.</strong>]]></message>
	<message key="admin.conference.pathImportInstructions">Existing conference path or path to create (e.g., "ocs").</message>
	<message key="admin.conference.importPath">OCS 1 path</message>
	<message key="admin.conference.importPathInstructions">Complete local filesystem path to the OCS 1 installation (e.g., "/var/www/ocs").</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.importRegistrations">Import registrations</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.emailUsers">Email created users with login information, including a random password</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.transcode">Transcode paper metadata from ISO8859-1</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.form.importPathRequired">The import path is required.</message>
	<message key="admin.conferences.importErrors">Importing failed to complete successfully</message>

	<!-- Site Administration Merge Users -->
	<message key="admin.mergeUsers">Merge Users</message>
	<message key="admin.mergeUsers.mergeUser">Merge User</message>
	<message key="admin.mergeUsers.into.description">Select a user to whom to attribute the previous user's submissions, editing assignments, etc.</message>
	<message key="admin.mergeUsers.from.description">Select a user (or several) to merge into another user account (e.g., when someone has two user accounts). The account(s) selected first will be deleted and any submissions, assignments, etc. will be attributed to the second account.</message>
	<message key="admin.mergeUsers.allUsers">All Enrolled Users</message>
	<message key="admin.mergeUsers.confirm">Are you sure you wish to merge the selected {$oldAccountCount} account(s) into the account with the username "{$newUsername}"? The selected {$oldAccountCount} accounts will not exist afterwards. This action is not reversible.</message>
	<message key="admin.mergerUsers.noneEnrolled">No enrolled users.</message>
</locale>
