<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE locale SYSTEM "../../lib/pkp/dtd/locale.dtd">

<!--
  * locale.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2000-2012 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Localization strings for the en_US (U.S. English) locale.
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<locale name="en_US" full_name="U.S. English">
	<message key="default.paperType.individual.name">Individual Submission</message>
	<message key="default.paperType.individual.description"></message>
	<message key="default.paperType.panel.name">Panel Submission</message>
	<message key="default.paperType.panel.description"></message>
	<message key="track.default.title">General Papers</message>
	<message key="track.default.abbrev">GEN</message>
	<message key="track.default.policy"></message>
	<message key="default.conferenceSettings.copyrightNotice"><![CDATA[Authors who submit to this conference agree to the following terms:<br/>
<strong>a)</strong>&nbsp;Authors retain copyright over their work, while allowing the conference to place this unpublished work under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Creative Commons Attribution License</a>, which allows others to freely access, use, and share the work, with an acknowledgement of the work's authorship and its initial presentation at this conference.<br/>
<strong>b)</strong>&nbsp;Authors are able to waive the terms of the CC license and enter into separate, additional contractual arrangements for the non-exclusive distribution and subsequent publication of this work (e.g., publish a revised version in a journal, post it to an institutional repository or publish it in a book), with an acknowledgement of its initial presentation at this conference.<br/>
<strong>c)</strong>&nbsp;In addition, authors are encouraged to post and share their work online (e.g., in institutional repositories or on their website) at any point before and after the conference.]]></message>

	<message key="default.schedConfSettings.checklist.notPreviouslyPublished">The submission has not been previously published, nor is it before another conference for consideration (or an explanation has been provided in Comments to the Director).</message>
	<message key="default.schedConfSettings.checklist.fileFormat">The submission file is in OpenOffice, Microsoft Word, RTF, or WordPerfect document file format.</message>
	<message key="default.schedConfSettings.checklist.addressesLinked"><![CDATA[All URL addresses in the text (e.g., <a href="http://pkp.sfu.ca">http://pkp.sfu.ca</a>) are activated and ready to click.]]></message>
	<message key="default.schedConfSettings.checklist.submissionAppearance">The text is single-spaced; uses a 12-point font; employs italics, rather than underlining (except with URL addresses); and all illustrations, figures, and tables are placed within the text at the appropriate points, rather than at the end.</message>
	<message key="default.schedConfSettings.checklist.anonymous">If submitting to a peer-reviewed track of the conference, authors' names are removed from submission, with "Author" and year used in the bibliography and footnotes, instead of authors' name, paper title, etc.</message>
	<message key="default.schedConfSettings.checklist.personalInformationRemoved">If submitting to peer review, all Microsoft Office documents (including Supplementary Files) have been saved by going to File and selecting Save As; clicking Tools (or Options in a Mac); clicking Security; selecting "Remove personal information from file properties on save"; clicking Save.</message>
	<message key="default.conferenceSettings.privacyStatement">The names and email addresses entered in this conference site will be used exclusively for the stated purposes of this conference and will not be made available for any other purpose or to any other party.</message>
	<message key="default.conferenceSettings.authorSelfArchivePolicy">Authors are permitted to post their papers on personal or institutional websites prior to and after publication by this conference (while providing the bibliographic details of that publication).</message>
	<message key="default.conferenceSettings.emailSignature"><![CDATA[________________________________________________________________________
{$conferenceName}
{$conferenceUrl}
]]></message>
	<message key="default.conferenceSettings.forReaders"><![CDATA[We encourage readers to sign up for notification of papers posted for this conference. We recommend that you review the <a href="{$aboutUrl}">About the Conference</a> page for the conference's policies, and visit the <a href="{$conferenceUrl}">Conference Homepage</a> to find out what conferences are coming up.]]></message>
	<message key="default.conferenceSettings.forAuthors"><![CDATA[Interested in submitting to this conference? We recommend that you review the <a href="{$aboutUrl}">About the Conference</a> page for the conference's policies, and visit the <a href="{$conferenceUrl}">Conference Homepage</a> to find out what conferences are coming up.]]></message>
	<message key="default.conferenceSettings.lockssLicense"><![CDATA[This conference utilizes the LOCKSS system to create a distributed archiving system among participating libraries and permits those libraries to create permanent archives of the conference for purposes of preservation and restoration. <a href="http://lockss.stanford.edu/">More...</a>]]></message>

	<message key="default.schedConfSettings.emailSignature"><![CDATA[________________________________________________________________________
{$conferenceName} {$schedConfName}
{$schedConfUrl}
]]></message>
	<message key="default.conferenceSettings.archiveAccessPolicy">The presentations that make up the current and archived conferences on this site have been made open access and are freely available for viewing, for the benefit of authors and interested readers.</message>
	<message key="default.schedConfSettings.checklist.bibliographicRequirements"><![CDATA[The text adheres to the stylistic and bibliographic requirements outlined in the <a href="{$authorGuidelinesUrl}">Author Guidelines</a>, which is found in About the Conference.]]></message>
	<message key="default.schedConfSettings.forReaders"><![CDATA[We encourage readers to sign up for notification of papers posted for this conference. Use the <a href="{$accountUrl}">Account</a> link at the top of the homepage for the conference. This list allows the conference to claim a certain level of support or readership. See the conference's <a href="{$privacyStatementUrl}">Privacy Statement</a> which assures readers that their name and email address will not be used for other purposes.]]></message>
	<message key="default.schedConfSettings.forAuthors"><![CDATA[Interested in submitting to this conference? We recommend that you review the <a href="{$aboutUrl}">About the Conference</a> page for the conference's track policies, as well as the <a href="{$authorGuidelinesUrl}">Author Guidelines</a>. Authors need to <a href="{$accountUrl}">create an account</a> with the conference prior to submitting, or if an account already exists, can simply <a href="{$loginUrl}">log in</a> and begin the submission process.]]></message>
</locale>
